<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>MATLAB on Aharon Sebton</title>
    <link>https://sebtona.github.io/techs/matlab/</link>
    <description>Recent content in MATLAB on Aharon Sebton</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Aharon Sebton 2023</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Nov 2021 12:30:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sebtona.github.io/techs/matlab/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Mathematical Image Reconstruction</title>
      <link>https://sebtona.github.io/portfolio/mathematical-image-reconstruction/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Nov 2021 12:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sebtona.github.io/portfolio/mathematical-image-reconstruction/</guid>
      <description>This MATLAB project completed in my Advanved Engineering Mathematics course demonstrates how eigenvectors and eigenvalues can be used for image re-synthesis and compression. I learned the following important takeaways by completing this project:
Any image can be represented as a set of eigenpairs (eigenvalues and corresponding eigenvectors). Original Cameraman Image and Plot of Eigenvalues
Some image eigenvalues have greater magnitudes than others. Magnitude of Eigenvalues of Image
When reconstructing an image, eigenvalues with greater magnitudes contribute more information to the image than eigenvalues with smaller magnitudes when paired with their corresponding eigenvectors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mathematical Edge Detection</title>
      <link>https://sebtona.github.io/portfolio/mathematical-edge-detection/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Oct 2021 12:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sebtona.github.io/portfolio/mathematical-edge-detection/</guid>
      <description>This MATLAB project completed in my Advanved Engineering Mathematics course demonstrates gradient and Laplacian edge detection techniques, and their caveats with grayscale images. I learned the following important takeaways by completing this project:
Taking the gradient of an image in any direction (by convolving the image with a kernel) will result in an intuitive visualization of how quickly pixel values change in said direction. This can be used as a crude edge detection method.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
