<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ROS on Aharon Sebton</title>
    <link>https://sebtona.github.io/designs/ros/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ROS on Aharon Sebton</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Aharon Sebton 2023</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 May 2023 17:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sebtona.github.io/designs/ros/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Gesture Controlled Drone Simulation</title>
      <link>https://sebtona.github.io/portfolio/gesture-controlled-drone-simulation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2023 17:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sebtona.github.io/portfolio/gesture-controlled-drone-simulation/</guid>
      <description>I worked in a team with two of my fellow students on a final project for our Biorobotics/Cybernetics class. The goals of the project were to create a machine learning model capable of accurately classifying a predetermined set of hand and arm gestures based on a user&amp;rsquo;s biosignals, and to use said model to control a quadcopter drone&amp;rsquo;s trajectory in a simulation environment.
We began this project by agreeing on a set of fifteen hand/arm gestures that map to commands for the drone to move and rotate along all axes in 3D space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sawyer Mobile Device Interaction</title>
      <link>https://sebtona.github.io/portfolio/sawyer-mobile-device-interaction/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 17:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sebtona.github.io/portfolio/sawyer-mobile-device-interaction/</guid>
      <description>For my final project in my Advanced Robotics class, I proposed a method of enabling the collaborative arm robot Sawyer (by Rethink Robotics) to perform single and multi-touch gestures on a mobile device. The purpose of this project is twofold. One is to allow for automated smartphone and mobile application testing through cobots. The other purpose is to eventually allow for cobot teleoperation through human biological signals, such as EMG or gaze, so that people with mobility-limiting disabilities may fully control touch screen devices without use of their arms.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
